Ali Raza



FRONTEND ENGINEER

Details

Islamabad, Pakistan



□ alirazamunir401@gmail.com

Links







Education

BS Software Engineering

Skills

Javascript

Typescript

ReactJS

Redux/Context/Zustand

HTML/CSS

Tailwind/Styled-Components

MUI/AntD/React-Bootstrap

SCSS

Webpack/Grunt

Node/Express

Mongoose/Sequelize/Knex

Profile

Frontend Developer with about 3 years of experience, specializing in React, JavaScript, and web development. Demonstrated ability to create high-performing and user-friendly web applications. Strong problem-solving skills and a passion for staying up-to-date with the latest technologies and industry trends.

Employment History

Software Engineer - Convo - NOV 2021 - PRESENT

- Designed and implemented efficient, testable, and reusable ReactJS components for the design library.
- Ported a custom Convo Chat SDK to vanillaJS, reducing server load by half.
- Developed dynamic teacher evaluation forms for the SOAR School, saving hours of manual work per week.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design and implement new features.
- Migrated an outdated AngularJS(v1.6) app to ReactJS.
- Worked on the FT7 team at Zoovu to fix confiscator bugs.
- · Worked on the i123 app for their quotation management engine.

Software Engineer - Septem Systems - AUG 2021 - NOV 2021

- I worked as a developer specializing in Vue2 and NodeJS.
- Redesign of the Audio Playground web app, resulting in a 20% increase in user engagement.
- · Worked on bigscoots.com project.

Software Engineer - Front-end - Markloops - AUG 2020 - JUNE 2021

- Worked on multiple MERN stack projects.
- Created a custom Shopify theme tailored to the specific requirements of organization, resulting in a reduction in development time.
- Proficiently converted design files including Figma, XD, and PDF, to HTML/CSS.
- Developed the complete frontend for dialboxx.pk.
- Collaborated with the product team at foodcartsmanufacturing.com to create the frontend of their site.

Internship

Software Engineer - QuellxCode - June 2020 - Aug 2020

- Developed the website quellxcode.com using ReactJS.
- Assisted senior developers in the implementation of new features and resolution of bugs.

Achievements

Recognized as a Key Contributor in Q3 2022 at Convo

Awarded the title of Ultimate Team Player in Q2 2022 at Convo

Achieved 950+ reputation on Stack Overflow

Received the Critical Thinking Certificate for securing 1st place in a school science fair.